<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code | Michael Schomaker</title>
    <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/tags/code/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>code</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/images/icon_hue888863bcf6448bbe1c2d7b1880687e8_12435_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>code</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/tags/code/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubly Robust Estimation of Average Treatment Effects on the Treated through Marginal Structural Models</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2023-05-11_msm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2023-05-11_msm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Statistics and Data Analysis - With Exercises, Solutions and Applications in R (Second updated and extended edition)</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2023-01-23_intro_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2023-01-23_intro_book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our introcutory book contains a comprehensive and thorough overview of fundamental statistical concepts such as hypothesis testing, inference and regression; and each
chapter is accompanied by a wealth of exercises and solutions. Have a look at the edicated 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/book/&#34;&gt;book page&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Delta-Method and Influence Function in Medical Statistics: a Reproducible Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2022-07-01_delta_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2022-07-01_delta_method/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating the Effect of Central Bank Independence on Inflation Using Longitudinal Targeted Maximum Likelihood Estimation</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2021-03-01_estimating_the_effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2021-03-01_estimating_the_effect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, there has been a lot of interest and discussion about the use of causal inference in economics. Whether it is feasible and whether there are benefits of working with a directed acyclic
graph (DAG) and a non-parametric structural equation framework, is one aspect of the debate. A summary on this discussion can be found in a working paper by Imbens (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.07271&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our paper, we are interested in a controversial macroeconomic question: does an independent central bank (CBI) reduce a country&amp;rsquo;s inflation? This question is causal in nature and certainly requires a causal inference approach
to be answered. We have made the effort to develop an elaborate DAG for this question based on economic theory and substantiated it with  literature as much as possible. Our suggestion is to commit to this causal model (i.e. the DAG),
motivate it in much detail, discuss possible violations of it, and ultimately conduct sensitivity analyses that evaluate effect estimates under different (structural) assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our analayses, we use the i) identifiability considerations from the derived DAG and ii) longitudinal targeted maximum likelihood estimation (LTMLE), a doubly robust estimation technique, 
in conjunction with data-adaptive estimation approaches (&amp;ldquo;super learning&amp;rdquo;) to derive our effect estimates. 
The advantage of using such an approach is that with LTMLE data-adaptive estimation can be used while still retaining valid inference (under assumptions). This reduces the risk of model mis-specification compared to estimation
techniques which require the commitment to parametric assumptions, such as inverse probability of treatment weighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While certainly challenging, our paper shows that even for complex macroeconomic questions, it is possible to develop a causal model and implement modern doubly robust longitudinal effect estimators. As with many questions in economics and 
the social sciences, one has to consider the possibility that some structural assumptions are incorrect. In our paper, we use both a purely data-adaptive approach as well as an approach motivated by economic theory to evaluate whether 
different, but meaningful, structural assumptions would lead to different estimates. 
Our main analysis (based on the developed DAG) suggests that if a country had legislated CBI for every year between 1998 and 2008, 
it would have had an average increase in inflation of 0.01 (95% confidence interval (CI): -1.48; 1.50) percentage points in 2010. 
The other two approaches, both of which make less structural assumptions, led to slightly different results: -0.44 (95% CI: -2.38; 1.59) and 0.01 (95% CI: -1.46; 1.47).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a monetary policy point of view, we could thus conclude  that there is no strong support for the hypothesis that an independent central bank necessarily lowers inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary: causal inference in economics, using directed acyclic graphs and modern doubly robust estimation strategies is challenging, but possible and certainly rewarding!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression and Causality</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2020-06-25_regression_causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2020-06-25_regression_causality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The causal effect of an intervention (treatment/exposure) on an outcome can be estimated by: i) specifying knowledge about the data-generating process; ii) assessing under what assumptions a target quantity, such as for example a causal odds ratio, can be identified given the specified knowledge (and given the measured data); and then, iii) using appropriate statistical estimation techniques to estimate the desired parameter of interest. As regression is the cornerstone of statistical analysis, it seems obvious to ask: is it appropriate to use estimated regression parameters for causal effect estimation? It turns out that using regression for effect estimation is possible, but typically requires more assumptions than competing methods. This manuscript provides a comprehensive summary of the assumptions needed to identify and estimate a causal parameter using regression and, equally important, discusses the resulting implications for statistical practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When and when not to use optimal model averaging</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2019-01-01_when_and_when_not_to/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2019-01-01_when_and_when_not_to/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Longitudinal Targeted Maximum Likelihood Estimation in Complex Settings with Dynamic Interventions</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2019-01-01_using_longitudinal_t/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2019-01-01_using_longitudinal_t/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paradoxical Collider Effect in the Analysis of Non-Communicable Disease Epidemiological Data: a reproducible illustration and web application</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2019-01-01_paradoxical_collider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2019-01-01_paradoxical_collider/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect Modification and Collapsibility in Evaluations of Public Health Interventions</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2019-01-01_effect_modification_/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2019-01-01_effect_modification_/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeted maximum likelihood estimation for a binary treatment: A tutorial</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2018-01-01_targeted_maximum_lik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2018-01-01_targeted_maximum_lik/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrap inference when using multiple imputation</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2018-01-01_bootstrap_inference_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2018-01-01_bootstrap_inference_/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For many analyses, it is common to use both bootstrapping and multiple imputation (MI): MI to address missing data and bootstrapping to obtain standard errors. For example, when using the g-formula in causal inference, bootstrapping is required to 
obtain standard errors; however, the data may be multiply imputed due to missing (baseline) data in the population of interest. How should bootstrapping and multiple imputation then be combined? First bootstrapping ($B$ times, including missing data) and then impute ($M$ times); or first impute and then bootstrap the multiply 
imputed data? For the latter approach, one could use bootstrapping to estimate the standard error in each imputed
data set and apply the standard MI combining rules (&amp;ldquo;Rubin&amp;rsquo;s rules&amp;rdquo;); alternatively, the $B \times M$ estimates could be pooled and 95% confidence
intervals could be calculated based on the 2.5th and 97.5th percentiles of the respective empirical distribution. For the
former  approach, either multiple imputation combining rules can be applied to the imputed data of each bootstrap sample
to obtain $B$ point estimates, which in turn, may be used to construct confidence intervals, or the $B \times M$ estimates of the
pooled data are used for interval estimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our paper, we evaluated the above four approaches and found that three are generally valid whereas one - first imputing, then bootstrapping, and then pooling the estimates - is invalid. We describe the advantages, disadvantages and implications
of all approaches and give guidance which approach may be suitable in which context. Under the &lt;em&gt;code&lt;/em&gt; tag above, an example on how to implement the four respective approaches is contained as well as code of the simulation studies from the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is nice about this manuscript is not only that it provides practical guidance, but also that it sparked some other interesting research. For instance, Bartlett and Hughes consider the combination of imputation and bootstrapping
when imputation and analysis models are uncongenial or misspecified (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1911.09980&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Interestingly, they find that bootstrapping, followed by imputation, and not pooling estimates, is the preferred 
approach in this case. This is in line with our suggested approach on model selection and averaging with multiply imputed data (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/project/mami/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Also, van Hippel and Bartlett proposed an
alternative, computationally efficient, point estimator and confidence interval when bootstraping followed by MI, which is implemented in an R-package (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/bootImpute/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bootImpute &lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is nice to see this work being used and further developed; also after this manuscript got initially rejected by an applied stats journal because a reviewer insisted: &amp;ldquo;There is nothing really new in the paper&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the risk of dolutegravir for women of childbearing potential</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2018-01-01_assessing_the_risk_o/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2018-01-01_assessing_the_risk_o/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Statistics and Data Analysis - With Exercises, Solutions and Applications in R</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2016-01-01_introduction_to_stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2016-01-01_introduction_to_stat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our introcutory book contains a comprehensive and thorough overview of fundamental statistical concepts such as hypothesis testing, inference and regression; and each
chapter is accompanied by a wealth of exercises and solutions. Have a look at the edicated 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/book/&#34;&gt;book page&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Treatment of Missing Data and Measurement Error in HIV Research Using Multiple Overimputation</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2015-01-01_simultaneous_treatme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2015-01-01_simultaneous_treatme/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model selection and model averaging after multiple imputation</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2014-01-01_model_selection_and_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2014-01-01_model_selection_and_/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-ignorable loss to follow-up: correcting mortality estimates based on additional outcome ascertainment</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2014-01-01_non-ignorable_loss_t/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2014-01-01_non-ignorable_loss_t/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrinkage averaging estimation</title>
      <link>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2012-01-01_shrinkage_averaging_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MichaelSchomaker.github.io/publication/2012-01-01_shrinkage_averaging_/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
